<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2025 on Alexander Atte</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/2025/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2025 on Alexander Atte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 07:57:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/2025/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/revelations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 07:57:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/revelations/</guid>
      <description>Another 365&amp;hellip; First and foremost I want to thank my mfing self for making it this far. [insert itaintmuch.jpg]
25 years of fucking around and finding out. Mindboggling stuff really. There&amp;rsquo;s been more ups than downs, more smiles than frowns and lots of in-betweeners. Truthfully speaking there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot more in-betweeners than there should&amp;rsquo;ve been, but as a great man once said; &amp;ldquo;ball up top brother&amp;rdquo;. No point sulking over matters like spilled milk.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-365&#34;&gt;Another 365&amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First and foremost&lt;/strong&gt; I want to thank my mfing self for making it this far.
[insert itaintmuch.jpg]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 years of fucking around and finding out. Mindboggling stuff really. There&amp;rsquo;s been more ups than downs, more smiles than frowns and lots of in-betweeners. Truthfully speaking there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot more in-betweeners than there should&amp;rsquo;ve been, but as a great man once said; &amp;ldquo;ball up top brother&amp;rdquo;. No point sulking over matters like spilled milk. Onward. Another great man almost religiously recites a quip I&amp;rsquo;ve found very helpful; &amp;ldquo;Observe. Adapt. Overcome.&amp;rdquo;  Words to live by in my honest opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now considering how delayed this space has been [insert itsbeen78years.jpg], I&amp;rsquo;ll just dive into the weeds. This is my digital space for long form thought, reviews, literally everything and anything. Ironic take but it&amp;rsquo;s my earth wire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without much ado, my primary goal this year is to create as much as possible. Movies, scripts, systems, web-apps, the list of prospects is not too long but its things I&amp;rsquo;ve had genuine interests in forever. January&amp;rsquo;s almost over and we&amp;rsquo;re off to a decent start, which is embarassing but net positive nontheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My secondary goal &amp;hellip; is to read 24 books. Done with first 2, 22 to go. Unreal how hard its been to recultivate a reading habit, my attention span&amp;rsquo;s been colosally fucked by bad habits but its been fun getting into again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarise each one; &amp;ldquo;Linux for Hackers&amp;rdquo; exposed me to a level of control over digital systems that most plebs are not used to. Most dont even need it either so cant blame them, on the other hand the applications are endless (basically everything runs on linux bro), data (generally speaking) becomes easier to manipulate, to clean, backup, store, remotely access etc, the only limit is imagination. Also considering I have technical ambitions CLI skills are very useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &amp;ldquo;The Lessons of History&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; probably the most knowledge/historically dense book I ever read, civilisation in my eyes has become this cyclical pvp game of human interactions on the micro/individual scale and the macro/state scale. Understand that competition is at the core of our biological being, society which is just the individual but magnified, is no different. Reading history has such grounding benefits that the fact the subject is no longer compulsory in my nations educational curiculum says an awful lot about the national agenda. Altogether this over simplification does no justice to the authors but its pretty accurate I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next two will be more of the same shuffliing between technical and anthropological themes, my library is brimming with random texts so every now and then there might be something else. But this is the template of choice. Moving forward, I&amp;rsquo;ll post my thoughts and tinkerings on here, lets see where we end up in 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
